We still have our two entities that have split up at the top and at the bottom of the screen.
At the top there is the LoRaWAN server.
And at the bottom there is the IoT platform with the user application.
Let's look at the uplink stream first.
In fact, if you think about it, the ideal solution isn't that the IoT platform requests the opening messages,
but instead it would be much better if the LoRaWAN server could push these messages without being
requested.
This is possible with the HTTP protocol, but the request will be different from the one we saw before.
This time the request is called an HTTP POST request and not HTTP GET.
In that case, the LoRaWAN server is the client and the IoT platform is the server to which we'll
connect to send the uplink messages.
With this way of proceeding, each time a data arrives, it's transmitted.
We can say that each time a data arrives it's POSTED.
Hence the name HTTP POST request. With an HTTP POST,
there is a very low latency between the time it arrives on the client and the time it arrives on the
IoT platform.
It's almost sent instantaneously.
For the downlink now, we'll have exactly the same approach.
The user downlink is stored on the IoT platform and in the same way the IoT platform will post the downlink
message using an HTTP POST request.
In that situation, the IoT platform is the client and the LoRaWAN server is the HTTP server.
With this way of doing it, each time a downlink message is generated by the user, it's transmitted
to the LoRaWAN server.
We can also say that it's POSTED, and therefore, there is a very low latency between the time the downlink
message is generated on the IoT platform and the time it arrives on the LoRaWAN server.
So let's make a demonstration of this and this time we'll do it in both directions:
So uplink and downlink messages.